guys let's do some calculus this says
find dydx for y equals natural log of e
to the X over e to the x minus 1. so
this is dealing with logarithms so first
thing we want to do is apply this rule
of logarithms the natural log of a over
C is equal to the natural log of a minus
the natural log of C so in this case the
top function is e to the X and this
bottom function is e to the x minus 1.
and next is another property of
logarithms we can use that the natural
log of e to the x is equal to X so this
first term can just be simplified to X
so let's take the derivative derivative
of x is equal to one and then we're
going to subtract and then for the
derivative of natural log let's use
these notes right here it's equal to the
derivative of x over X so let's do our
fraction here where we put X on bottom
but X is this whole e to the x minus 1
and then on top is the derivative of
this and the derivative of this is just
e to the X and the derivative of
negative 1 is 0. so now we're
technically done but we can clean it up
a little bit let's give these two terms
a common denominator we'll multiply top
and bottom by e to the x minus one so
now this times one is just this and we
can smush these together these have a
common denominator so we can combine
them into a single fraction where we
just do this minus this and e to the x
minus E to the X goes away and so we're
just left with negative 1 over e to the
x minus one and that's the answer to the
question we can put a box around it you
guys want to try more calculus problems
I have a link down in the description
how exciting